A Guide to the Allen Telford Edmunds papers, 1917-2000
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Allen Telford Edmunds papers, 1917-2000
The Library of Virginia
43432
1.32 cu. ft. and 3 boxes
Allen Telford Edmunds
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James and Harriet Edmunds of Kill Devil Hills, North Carolina
Biographical Information
Allen Telford Edmunds was born 8 December 1903 near Banfield, Michigan, to Arthur Madison Edmunds and Grace Fisher Edmunds. Edmunds graduated from Michigan State College in 1926 and did post-graduate work at the National Recreation School at New York University in 1928-1929. He worked as superintendent of recreation for Amsterdam, New York, starting in 1929, and began working for the National Park Service in 1937. During World War II, Edmunds served in the United States Navy. He returned to the Park Service after the war. Edmunds' work was key in establishing parks along the Great Lakes and along the Atlantic and Gulf Coast shores. Edmunds retired from the Park Service in 1969, but remained as a special assistant to the regional director of the Philadelphia office of the National Park service until 1976. Edmunds married Margaret Rae Sleight (d. 1981) 20 June 1929 and they had two sons. Edmunds died 16 January 1985 in Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1917-2000, of Allen Telford Edmunds (1903-1985) of Michigan and Richmond, Virginia, consisting of biographical information on Edmunds; correspondence; family budgets; Edmunds' travelogues; secondary, high school, and college diplomas; accounts of his work in the National Park Service (NPS); reports on NPS projects he worked on along the Great Lakes and the Atlantic Coast; scrapbook and brochures from his participation in the World Recreation Congress in Japan and Taiwan in 1964; professional certificates and awards; college yearbook; and other papers.
Contents List
- Biographical information (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Family budgets, 1938-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Another side of the National Park Service (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Institute of Park Executives, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society Gold Pugsley award, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Certificate and citation from the Department of the Interior, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Slide show presentations (scripts only): introductory material, National Park Service in Crisis-Yes or No, Brief Items on China, India-Sri Lanka-Nepal, National Parks are Where You Find Them, Hungary-Poland-Romania, The Balkan States (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Slide show presentations (scripts only): Egypt-Jordan-and Israel and Rome, Italy, Russia and Scandinavian Nations, Mexico, Let's Worship Here, A Journey to Antiquity, Portugal and Spain-the People the Palaces the Cathedrals, The Constant Vigil (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Slide show presentations (scripts only): Glimpses of Parks and Gardens-Europe and the Orient, A Whisper of the Orient, The Great Lakes Shoreline Survey (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous papers (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Humor (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Kenbridge United Methodist Church (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The North Call, early and late March 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Mackinaw Journal, 19 February 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Clippings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Central Southeastern Regional Recreation Study--Interim report, August 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Our Fourth Shore: Great Lakes Shoreline, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore: draft General Management Plan, January 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore: General Management Plan, September 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Information on the Great Lakes National Lakeshore areas (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Special Reconnaissance Atlantic Coast Areas, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Our Vanishing Shoreline (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Great Beach Area: Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Cape Cod: A Proposed National Seashore Field Investigation Report, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cape Cod National Seashore Economic Impact Study, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Saint-Gaudens Memorial, Cornish, New Hampshire (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Hyde Park, New York, as a Seat for United Nations Organization, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Recreational Potential of Essex County, Vermont, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Information on Seashore parks (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Mission 66 program (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Scrapbook of visit to Japan and Taiwan, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- World Recreation Congress--National Parks of Japan, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- World Recreation Congress--National Parks of the New Republic of China [Taiwan], 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- National Recreation Association of Japan (Box 2, Folder 12)
- National Parks of Japan (2 booklets) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Guide to Tenrikyo (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Kinki: The Center Land of Japan (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hokkaido, Japan (3 booklets) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Kagoshima, Kyusyu, Japan (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Kyushu, Japan (2 booklets) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Sleeping Bear Dunes National Lakeshore: Hearings before the Subcommittee on National Parks and Recreation, 8-9 June 1970 (Box 3)
- Michigan State University Alumni Varsity Lettermen Directory, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
- Global View of Recreation, World Recreation Congress, 2-7 October 1964 (Box 3)
- The Wolverine, Michigan State College yearbook, 1924 (Box 3)
- Hotel San-ai (Box 3)
- State of Michigan 8th grade diploma, 2 June 1917 (Box 3)
- Bedford High School (Bedford, Michigan), diploma, 29 May 1919 (Box 3)
- Battle Creek High School (Battle Creek, Michigan), diploma, 21 June 1921 (Box 3)
- Michigan State College (University) diploma, 21 June 1926 (Box 3)
- Municipal Training School for City and Village Recreation Officials certificate, 18 April 1935 (Box 3)